Guide to the Reston Community Association Planning and Zoning Committee records, 1961-1997
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: Subject Files, 1961-1980; (11 boxes)
  - Summary of Adopted Long Range Plans for Fairfax County, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    3.06
  - Summary and Evaluation of Public Testimony on the Comprehensive Planning Program, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    11.14
  - Survey of Sewer Capacity in Northern Fairfax County, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    1.07
  - Tactical Considerations for New Town Citizens Groups: An Urban Guerilla Warfare Manual, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    1.01
  - Town of Herndon, Virginia, Zoning District Map, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    5.24
  - Traffic Survey, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    9.09
  - Transportation Inventory, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    1.06
  - Transportation Plan, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    5.20
  - Transportation Plan, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    5.21
  - Unsortable, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    7.07
  - Upper Potomac Planning District Comprehensive Plan Meeting, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    5.08
  - Use of the Name "Reston", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    7.11
  - Utilities Survey for Fairfax County, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    2.17
  - Volume 2: Financial Plan, Fiscal Year Five Year Countywide Development Program, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    7.10
  - Wastewater Management Inventory, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    1.08
  - Whiele Gas Station, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    10.01
- Series 2: Chronological Files, 1965-2011; (13.5 boxes)
  The documents titles are similar to series one while others are merely titled with the project number. All of these documents relate to planning and zoning projects in Reston.
  - Palindrone Corporation-Loan from Hercer Corporation, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    470.17
  - Parcel 12-Section 1, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 3rd Addition-Reston Planning Committee, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 4th Addition-Reston Planning Committee, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Palindrone Corporation-Loan from Hercer Corporation, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    470.18
  - B-587 Industrial, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    519.14
  - Recorded Releases-Reston 2570-505, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    470.19
  - C-167 Industrial, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    520.23
  - B-726 Section 4, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    520.16
  - B-732 Parcel 14, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    520.15
  - Division of Land Use (Case No. B-901, Zoned RE-2), 1968 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - B-824 Industrial, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    520.8
  - R-86-C-121 Section 931, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    519.20
  - B-847 Industrial, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    519.1
  - Inn Conference Center, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 7th Addition-Reston Planning Committee (No. C-20), 1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Newton Square, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 4)
    470.13
  - Newton Square Easement, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 5)
    470.10
  - Amerian Security and Loan, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 6)
    470.2
  - Newton Square, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    470.12
  - inn Conference Center, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    470.4
  - American Secuirty and Loan, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    470.3
  - C-203, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    520.1
  - 8th Addition Rezoning Case C-70 Section 26, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 9th Addition Rezoning Application-C-99, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - C-183, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    508.1
  - C-149, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    508.2
  - Revision To 2nd Addition to 1st Reston Planning Committee, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Case C-135 10th Addition Reston Planning Committee, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - C-196 Section 17/4, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    520.22
  - C-281, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    520.3
  - C-280, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    520.2
  - Rezoning Case C-279-16th Addition, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    510.10
  - American Secuity and Loan, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    470.1
  - Loan From gulf Oil Corporation 3.7 Million Dollars 2nd Trust Uncoveyed Reston, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    470.20
  - Rezoning Matters-General, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    470.21
  - Rezoning, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    470.22
  - Rezoning, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    470.23
  - Gulf Reston Rezoning, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    470.24
  - Gulf Reston, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    470.25
  - Gulf Reston Rezoning 18th Addition to East Reston Planning Committee, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    470.26
  - Blueprints, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Blueprints, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Blueprints, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - C-432 Industrial, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    519.8
  - Gulf Reston, Incorporated AMend A-502, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    470.30
  - Gulf Reston C-337 Rezoning-309.4571 18th Addition to 1st Reston Planning Committee, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    470.27
  - Gulf Reston, Incorporated C-432 Rezone 3.7436, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    470.29
  - Gulf Reston C-377 Rezoning-309.4571-18th Addition to 1st Reston Planning Committee, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Zoning Case C-377 18th Addition, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    510.2
  - Zoning Case C-377 18th Addition, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    510.3
  - Beverly Hospital Site Withdrawn, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    510.8
  - C-377 and 378 Reston Avenue Improvements, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    520.20
  - Zoning Case C-377 18th Addition, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    520.19
  - Development Plan Amedments-5 Parcels, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    510.6
  - Development Plan Amendments-5 Parcels, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    510.5
  - Newton Square Bylaws, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    470.14
  - New Square Articles of Incorporation, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    470.15
    - Articles of Incorporation: Newton Square Association, April 4, 1979; 1.
  - Reston Zoning, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    507.3
  - 21st Addition 1st Reston Planning Committee-Reston Zoning 76-C-111, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    510.15
  - Amendment to 5th Addition 1st Reston Planning Committee Case B-846 (Reston Zoning), 1977 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    510.14
  - Batchelder School Site, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    510.9
  - DP-119 Amendment to C-378, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    510.4
  - Clarke Farm Zoning 77-C-075, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    510.1a
  - Clark Farm Zoning, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    510.16
  - Newton Square Easement and Operating Agreement, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    470.5
  - DP 124 Section 15A/3A, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    519.3
  - 78-11-SUP Master Plan Revisions, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    519.4
  - DP 123 Section 4/2, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    519.7
  - DP 125 Section 36, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    519.9
  - DP 128 Sections 70 and 76, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    519.2
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    470.16
  - Newton Square Easement and Operating Agreement Section 905, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    470.11
  - Gulf Reston Incorporated Easement and Operating Agreement, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    470.6
  - Newton Square Easement and Operating Agreement, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    470.7
  - Newton Square Easement and Operating Agreement, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    470.8
  - DP-127, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    520.21
  - Reston Zoning, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    507.2
  - Reston Zoning, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    507.1
  - 80-C-013 Parcel 14 (Sunset Hills Road), 1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    519.15
  - DPA-C-555-1, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    519.5
  - DPA-C-279 Section 54-2A, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    519.6
  - Rezoning Case A502 2nd Submission, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    510.7
  - Newton Square Easement and Operating Agreement, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    470.9
  - DPA 79-C-032 Sections 31 and 35, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    520.12
  - 80 C and D-111, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    520.5a
  - 80 C and D-111, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    520.5b
  - Reston Zoning 81-C-118, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    510.13
  - Reston Zoning, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    507.5
  - Reston Zoning 81-C-086 Proposed, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    510.12
  - DPA C-377 Section 82, Block 2A, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    519.24
  - DPA A-936-2 Section 30, Block 2A, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    519.18
  - Reston Zoning 82C-060, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    519.11
  - Reston Zoning, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    507.4
  - Reston Zoning 83-C-040, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    519.12
  - Reston Zoning 83-C-039, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    519.13
  - Reston Zoning 85-C-005, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    519.10
  - Reston Zoning 82-C-074 Sections 41 and 45, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    519.16
  - Reston Zoning 80-C and D-111-B, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    519.19
  - DPA 80-C and D-111-2 Section 49, Parcels 11-3, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    520.6
  - DPA 79-C-032-2 Section 33,4B,5, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    520.11
  - DPA 80-C and D-111 Section 45, Parcels 11-3, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    520.4
  - Reston Zoning 86-C-119, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    520.10
  - Reston Zoning, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    507.7
  - Reston Zoning, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    507.6
  - DPA C-20, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    508.3
  - Reston Zoning 84-C-117 Section 43, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    520.14
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    510.11
  - Area E R2 86-C023, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    519.23a
  - Area E R2 86-C-023, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    519.23b
  - Area E R2 86-C023, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    519.22
  - Reston Zoning DPA 79-C-032-3 Section 69, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    507.8
  - Reston Zoning 86-C-121, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    508.5
  - Reston Zoning 85-C-088, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    508.4
  - Reston Zoning 86-C-118 (Concurrent with Reston Zoning 85-C-088, Reston Zoning C-121, Reston Zoning C-119), 1987 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    519.21
  - Reston Zoning 87-C-088 Section 83-1, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    520.13
  - A-502, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    519.17
  - Reston Zoning 89-D-052 Section 49, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    520.9
  - Reston Zoning 89-C-052, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    519.25
  - DPA 77-C-076-2 Section 78, Block 3, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - DPA 80-C-111-4 Section 59, Block 4, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    520.7
  - DRPA 84-C-117, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    520.17
  - DRPA 84-C-117, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    520.18
  - Reston Area Planning Documents and Maps, 2005-2010 (Oversize Mapcase 3, Folder 1)
    4 sets of maps (including one duplicate) showing plans for the Hunter Mill District and the Northern Virginia Stream Restoration project.
  - Reston Area Planning Documents and Maps, 2010-2011 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Conceptual Site Plan for Fairways Apartments near Lake Anne; Site Plan for the Spectrum Shopping Center into a mixed-use development; Block 16 owned by Boston Properties at the Town Center. The last remaining lot that has not been developed inside the current boundary of the Town Center.; Comstock Site Plan (Conceptual) for the parking garage and mixed use development for the Wiehle Metro station.